A Guide to the University of Virginia Board of Visitors Standing and Special Committee Records, 1992-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Board of Visitors Standing and Special Committee Records 1992-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/1/3.081
This collection consists of ca. 1,525 items (10 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restricted for ten years from the date of creation. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia. Access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or if permission is granted by the Secretary of the Board.
Acquisition Information
These papers were transferred from the Office of the Board of Visitors by Jeanne F. Bailes, Clerk of the Board of Visitors, on February 6, 2008.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of the University of Virginia Board of Visitors consists of the records of the standing and special committees of the Board of Visitors, 1992-2006, ca. 1,525 items (10 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear feet) chiefly minutes, correspondence, executive session records, administrative and topical files, confidential materials and memoranda. Also present is a folder concerning Hovey S. Dabney, the University of Virginia's thirty-fifth Rector (1992-1998).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series: Series I: The Papers of the Board of Visitors and Series II: Restricted Files. Within the series folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
Contents List
- Series I: Papers of the Board of Visitors
  - Ad Hoc Committee, regarding Dr. Alston's appeal 1998 March-June, 5 items (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Audit and Compliance Committee 2004 June-2005 September, 24 items (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee 2005 March-June, 16 items (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee 2005 August-December, 35 items (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Committee Minutes 2006 September-2007 February, 20 items (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Committee Minutes 2007 March-June, 18 items (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Committee Summaries 2004 October-2005 September, 6 items (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Dabney, Hovey Slayton - Papers of the Rector 1990-1994, 86 items (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Dabney, Hovey Slayton - Papers of the Rector 1994 - 2007, 48 items (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Educational Policy Committee 2005 January-September, 26 items (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Executive Committee 2005 January-September, 15 items (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Executive Committee 2005 November, 8 items (Box-folder 2:5)
  - External Affairs Committee 2005 September (Box-folder 2:6)
  - External Affairs Committee 2005 January-August, 29 items (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Finance Committee 2005 January-March, 11 items (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Finance Committee 2005 May-September, 23 items (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Institutional Performance Agreement 2000 October 16, 1 item (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Investment Management Company 2006 November, 1 item (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Investment Management Company 2007 March-May, 2 items (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Medical Center Operating Board 2003 October-2005 April, 34 items (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Medical Center Operating Board 2005 May-August, 39 items (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Medical Center Operating Board 2005 September-October, 23 items (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Medical Center Operating Board 2005 December, 26 items (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Medical Center Operating Board – Quality Subcommittee 2005 April-December, 16 items (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Meetings - Called 1990 April-July, 20 items (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Meetings - Full Board - Policy Discussion 2005-2006 February, 11 items (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Meetings - Joint - Finance and Student Affairs and Athletics Committees 2001 May-July, 40 items (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Meetings - Open 2004 December-2005 April, 46 items (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Meetings – Open 2005 May-October, 54 items (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Meetings - Open 2005 October-2006 February, 33 items (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Meetings - Open 2006 January-April, 52 items (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Meetings - Open 2006 April-June, 32 items (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Meetings - Open 2006 August-October, 36 items (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Meetings - Telephonic 2000 February-October, 20 items (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Meetings - Telephonic 2005 April 11, 3 items (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2001 October - 2005 May, 35 items (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2005 June- December, 59 items (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Professorships and Naming Committee 2004 January-October, 36 items (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Professorships and Naming Committee 2004 November-2005 March, 19 items (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Professorships and Naming Committee 2005 April - September, 34 items (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Retreat 1991 May - 1992 August, 25 items (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Retreat 1995 May - 1996 June, 50 items (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Retreat 1997 May - July, 30 items (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Retreat 1998 May - June, 58 items (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Retreat 1998 July (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Retreat 1999 April - June, 14 items (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Retreat 1999 July - August, 56 items (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Retreat 1999 July - August (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Retreat - Medical Center Operating Board 2005 May - August, 36 items (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Retreat - Medical Center Operating Board 2005 May - August (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Special Committee on Diversity 2005 January - September, 24 items (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Special Committee on Governance 2003 June - 2004 February, 47 items (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Special Committee on Governance - Minutes 2003 June - 2004 February, 9 items (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee 2003 April - 2005 September, 36 items (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Summer Orientation 2001 - 2006, 5 items (Box-folder 9:4)
  - University of Virginia at Wise Committee 2005 February - September, 24 items (Box-folder 9:5)
- Series II: Restricted Files
  - Dabney, Hovey Slayton - Papers of the Rector 1990 - 1992, 2 items (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Executive Session 2003 April - 2005 September, 11 items (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Medical Center Operating Board 2005 May - December, 26 items (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Meetings - Open 2005 June 3, 1 item (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Professorships and Naming Committee 2003 - 2005, 18 items (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Retreat 1997 July 8, 1 item (Box-folder 10:6)